Khushkaran Bajwa

Derby, United Kingdom 07595877695 me@khushkaran.com http://khushkaran.com

I am a software engineer with several years of experience in developing web apps and mobile applications. Development is much more than writing code, a developer should be able to cover the breakdown of a problem through to the deployment of the solution. I subscribe to the Software Craftsmanship Manifesto, passionate about Agile Development, BDD and am always looking for avenues to professionally and personally advance myself.

Technical Skills

Likes: ruby ruby-on-rails elixir git angularjs redis reactjs couchdb pouchdb

Experience

Developer - OLM Group

Oct 2015 → Current

rtc, git, java, reactjs, maven, tomcat, hibernate, spring, yui, javascript, react-redux, couchdb

Assist in the development of a case recording software and finance package using a custom framework based upon Spring and YUI. The core platform is deployed in house and managed by a dedicated team.

The projects require exceptional communication between the various teams and product owners. Testing also plays a big part in development using JUnit and Cucumber but never underplaying the importance of QA Testing.

Develop a successful, saleable high-fidelity protoype of a financial assessment application that was required to work offline. I was heavily involved in all aspects of it, from architecture and design to front-end and back-end. We ensured that we always followed best practice and had tests to increase our confidence in the code.

Developer - Causeway Technologies

Aug 2014 → Oct 2015

ruby, ruby-on-rails, jquery, angularjs, reactjs, elixir, phoenix, bdd, amazon-web-services, postgresql, redis, heroku, amazon-cloudfront, amazon-s3, json, amazon-ec2, rspec, capybara, cucumber, karma-runner, mocha, sinon, chai, sass, less

Develop a distributed app deployment and administration platform using Ruby on Rails. The front end of the platform and the administration is written with AngularJS whilst the administration apps are written in ReactJS. Other applications are also written in NodeJS and Sinatra. Also developed an Elixir API with the Phoenix web framework to provide User Details to the apps within the platform.

The core platform is deployed on an EC2 instance using Capistrano connected to a PostgreSQL RDS instance. A Redis ElastiCache instance is used as a store for queued jobs. The administration apps, being static, are deployed on S3 and the apps are stored on Heroku.

Whilst Object Oriented methodologies are important, equally important are writing readable and maintainable code. Testing is necessary to ensure that what written works to the correct specification and what will be written doesn't affect current features adversely. Mocha, Chai, Sinon and Karma is used to test the Javascript, RSpec for acceptance testing of the API and Cucumber is used for end-to-end testing.

Developer – Kesri Nishaan

 $2011 \rightarrow 2014$

objective-c, html5, css, php, javascript, jquery, mysql, linux, cocos2d-iphone, osx, ios, xml, json, ajax, websocket

Develop iOS app that retrieved files stored online for offline reading at a later point. Develop iOS app that retrieved a curated list of online streams that were able to be played back by users. Both apps required the UI/UX design for both iPhone and iPad alongside the design work such as icons and logos.

Develop iOS app that incorporated a game of a falling leaf that needed to collect photons for points but avoid getting hit by branches of trees. The game was developed using Cocos2D and was developed for iPhones, iPads and Macs.

A service, written PHP, was deployed to a linux server that interacted with the Apple Push Notification Service (APNS) to deliver push notifications to users of the apps that accepted this option.

Developer – Adaptive

Jul 2014 → Sep 2014

php, jquery, bootstrap, javascript, angularjs

Developed PHP/JavaScript powered websites that provided information to end users about events, news and contact information for a farming corporation.

Developed E-commerce PHP/JavaScript powered website, for the sale of of school uniform, alongside a backend stock control system and ordering for a big seller of school uniform.

Education

Developer Bootcamp – Makers Academy

git, linux, ruby, sinatra, rspec, capybara, ruby-on-rails, jquery, javascript, heroku, websocket, ajax, jasmine, sass, less

For my final project, I worked on SL8, an app that allowed students to request the attention of tutors by asking questions. This was to replace students having to write their name on the whiteboard. The tutor then would work their way around to them, and mark off the answers through the mobile site. If the list grew too long, using Twilio, it would send an SMS to the teach to inform them. All code was tested using RSpec and Capybara.

BA (Hons) Accounting & Finance – University of Derby

2008 → 2011

 $2014 \rightarrow 2014$

objective-c, html5, css, php, javascript, jquery, mysql, linux, osx, ios, xml, json, ajax, websocket

Developed an iOS app that allowed the simple calculation of company statements as a hobby.

Projects & Interests

baanis - https://github.com/khushkaran/baanis

Jun 2015 → Current

ruby

Baanis in CSV format with Transliteration and Translation

Apps & Software

Dhur Ki Baani 2 - https://itunes.apple.com/app/id542304351

ios, iphone, objective-c, json

Dhur Ki Baani is an iOS app that allows users to listen to select internet radio stations.

iOS Application Developer and UI/UX Designer

iNitnem – https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/initnem/id585671164?ls=1&mt=8 ios, objective-c, json, iphone

iNitnem is an iOS app that allows users to read and listen to Sikh Prayers.

iOS Application Developer and UI/UX Designer

Tools

First Computer: Commodore 64

Favorite Editor: VIM